A Finding Aid to the James Brooks and Charlotte Park Papers, 1909-2010, bulk 1930-2010, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Charlotte Park papers, 1930s-2010; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 15-18, OV 23
  - Subject Files, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
    - Art Lending Service, Museum of Modern Art, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - James Brooks: A Catalogue Raisonné, circa 1998-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - James Brooks and Charlotte Park Brooks Foundation, circa 2002-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - The Pollock-Krasner Foundation, Inc., 1989-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Quotations about Art typed by Cile Downs, circa 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Teaching, circa 1955-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Type Samples, Hampton Press, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Women's Group, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Brooks Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
    - ACA Galleries, Munich, James Brooks: Works from the 50s and 60s (1999 March 4-May 29), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Artemis-Greenberg Van Doren Gallery, James Brooks: Selected Paintings: 1960-1985 (2003 October 8-November 5), 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Greenberg Van Doren Gallery Exhibition (2005 Fall), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Guild Hall, James Brooks in Retrospect (2001 October 6 -2002 January 6), 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
    - Manny Silverman Gallery Exhibition (2005), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - The Parrish Art Museum, The Stamp of Impulse: Abstract Expressionist Prints (2002 August 4-October 13), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - The Sage Colleges, The New York School: Another View (2005 January 24-March 30), 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Tampa Museum of Art, Modern Art in Florida: 1948-1970 (2003 April 22-July 15), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Brooks and Park Exhibition, Spanierman Gallery, L.L.C., Artists and Nature on Eastern Long Island: 1940-the Present (2005 July 22-September 2), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Park Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
    - Anita Shapolsky, Women of the 50's (2002 September 25-November 23), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Elinor Poindexter Gallery, Joellen Hall, Cile Downs, Mary Lincoln Bonnel, Betty Klavun, Charlotte Park (1984 December 1-26), 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 28-29)
    - Ingberger Gallery, Ltd. Show (1979 December 1-19), 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Personal Business Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
    - Auction Records, Brooks, 1993-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Bills, Paid, 1993-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Conservation, Brooks, 1994-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Conservation, Park, 2002-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Conservation, Other Artists, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Gifts, Artwork by Brooks, Archival Resource Key (Box 16)
      - The Brooklyn Museum, 1994-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Columbia Museum of Art, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - The Farnsworth Art Museum, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - Dan Flavin, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - Norton Museum of Art, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 40)
      - The Portland Art Museum, 2002-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 41)
      - Southern Methodist University, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 42)
      - Telfair Museum of Art, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Gifts, Artwork by Park, 2001-2004; 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Insurance, 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Inventories, Brooks, 1992; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Inventories, Brooks Paintings at Crozier, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Inventories, Brooks Works on Paper, circa 1994-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Inventories, Park, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Lists of Paintings by Park, circa 1970s-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Loans, Brooks and Park, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Loans, Park, 1970s-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Mailing Lists, 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Prices, Brooks, circa 1993-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Prices, Park, circa 1965-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Publication/Reproduction Permissions, Brooks, 1998-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Receipts, Brooks, 1992-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Receipts, Park, 1959; 1974-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Royalties (VAGA), Brooks, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Sales, Brooks, 1992-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Sales, Park, circa 1959-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Storage, Park, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Storage and Shipping, Brooks, circa 1994-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Walsh, John (Attorney, Estate of James Brooks), 1992-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Washburn Gallery Agreement, Brooks, 1992-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Printed Material, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
    - Articles about/mentioning Charlotte Park, circa 1945-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23-25)
    - Articles about/mentioning James Brooks, 1992-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Articles, Miscellaneous, circa 1949-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 27-30)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Brooks, 1993-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Other Artists, circa 1950-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Park, circa 1953-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 33-35)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Brooks, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Brooks, 1997-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Other Artists, 1961-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3-8)
      Oversized material housed in OV 23.
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Park, circa 1953-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Items mentioning Brooks, circa 2000-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Items mentioning Park, 1974-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Items, circa 1972-2004; Archival Resource Key; Oversized material housed in OV 23. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Obituaries, circa 1950s-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
  - Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Photographic Materials, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
    - Artwork by Park, circa 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Artwork by Park (Negatives), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Artwork by Park (Slides), circa 1970s-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Artwork by Others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Exhibition Installations, Mathews Gallery, Houston, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Exhibition Installations, The Parrish Art Museum, Three East End Artists (2003), Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Exhibition Installations, Unidentified Venue, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Charlotte Park, circa 1940s-2004; Archival Resource Key; Includes negatives and slides. (Box 18, Folder 24-25)
    - Charlotte Park at Muir Woods (1945), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Charlotte Park in Studio [with curator Meg Perlman?], 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Charlotte Park with Others, 1962-2001; 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 28-29)
    - Park Family, circa 1979-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Photograph Album, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Hawkes-Park Family Graves, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalogs, Other Artists, from box 18, Folder 6, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 23)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous Printed Items, General, from Box 18, Folder 13, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 23)
- Unprocessed Addition, circa 1930-2010; Series 12; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 25-26
  The unprocessed addition, received in 2017, includes 58 "week-at-a-glance" appointment books, three journals and one address/ telephone book of Charlotte Park; a hand written chronology with significant dates and notes; postcards and exhibition announcements sent to Charlotte and James; doodles; and a sketch, possibly by Don Kingman.
  - Unprocessed Papers, circa 1930-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 25)
  - Unprocessed Papers, circa 1930-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 26)